=A Puppetry=
= دمية =
=Episode 15=
= الحلقة 15 =
Youhai.
يوهاي.
What do you think?
ماذا تعتقد؟
You look different today.
تبدو مختلفًا اليوم.
Is it that obvious?
هل هذا واضح؟
You can tell it right away.
يمكنك أن تقول ذلك على الفور.
You grow up before my eyes.
أنت تكبر أمام عيني.
I have seen everything about you.
لقد رأيت كل شيء عنك.
Then he will be able to notice too.
ثم سيكون قادرًا على ملاحظة ذلك أيضًا.
He?
هو؟
Who?
من؟
It's a secret.
إنه سر.
Song.
أغنية.
Ke.
متي.
Yang.
أيّ.
Song Keyang.
سونغ كيانغ.
Look at me.
انظر إليَّ.
What?
ماذا؟
Take a proper look.
ألق نظرة مناسبة.
Okay.
تمام.
And they say...
ويقولون...
(Marionette) The sky is starry but the moon is gloomy.
(ماريونيت) السماء مليئة بالنجوم لكن القمر قاتم.
The world is full of lives but justice does not prevail.
العالم مليء بالأرواح ولكن العدل لا يسود.
Amazing movement.
حركة مذهلة.
This is the signature technique of the Chen Theater Troupe.
هذه هي تقنية توقيع فرقة مسرح تشين.
I train for this
أنا أتدرب من أجل هذا
since young.
منذ الصغر.
With a flick
بنقرة واحدة
of these few fingers,
من هذه الأصابع القليلة ،
I could manipulate the strings.
يمكنني التلاعب بالخيوط.
There are so many nuances to it.
هناك الكثير من الفروق الدقيقة لذلك.
Right.
الصحيح.
Once upon a time,
كان ياما كان،
in a remote town,
في بلدة نائية ،
there was
كان يوجد
a smart, cute,
ذكي ، لطيف ،
and kind
ولطيف
lady.
السيدة.
Unfortunately,
للأسف،
shortly before her birthday,
قبل عيد ميلادها بقليل ،
something bad happened to her family.
حدث شيء سيء لعائلتها.
When she lost all hope,
عندما فقدت كل أمل ،
a
أ
handsome man appeared.
ظهر رجل وسيم.
Appeared!
ظهر!
This man promised
وعد هذا الرجل
to bring her happiness,
لتجلب لها السعادة ،
to give her
لمنحها
the will to live amid hardship.
الرغبة في العيش وسط الضيق.
They shared
هم شاركوا
many beautiful memories.
ذكريات جميلة كثيرة.
The man said
قال الرجل
he would bring her
سيحضرها
to visit
لزيارة
his hometown.
مسقط رأسه.
Visit his hometown.
قم بزيارة مسقط رأسه.
He also said
كما أنه قال
they should hold hands
يجب أن يمسكوا أيديهم
and travel far away.
والسفر بعيدًا.
(He doesn't care about me at all.)
(إنه لا يهتم بي على الإطلاق).
(He didn't even notice anything.)
(لم يلاحظ أي شيء حتى).
Yay!
ياي!
Done.
فعله.
I never had the time
لم يكن لدي الوقت قط
to get you a present
لتحصل على هدية لك
for your birthday.
لعيد ميلادك.
Now, I drew a painting.
الآن ، رسمت لوحة.
So?
لذا؟
Are you surprised?
هل انت متفاجئ؟
Shocked?
صدمت؟
Why are you upset?
لماذا أنت مستاء؟
Is it not beautiful enough?
أليست جميلة بما فيه الكفاية؟
You look cute.
تبدين لطيفة.
What's the matter?
ما الأمر؟
Song Keyang.
سونغ كيانغ.
You didn't notice me.
أنت لم تلاحظني.
A plum makeup with pearls.
ماكياج البرقوق مع اللؤلؤ.
I already noticed it.
لقد لاحظت ذلك بالفعل.
(Once I master the Flesh Puppet)
(بمجرد أن أتقن دمية اللحم)
(and the voodoo arts,)
(وفنون الشعوذة)
(I can then use)
(يمكنني بعد ذلك استخدام)
(Yuji Puppet to unlock the treasure)
(دمية Yuji لفتح الكنز)
(and obtain the Book of Yuji.)
(واحصل على كتاب Yuji.)
(Voodoo arts.)
(فنون الفودو.)
(The treasure map.)
(خريطة الكنز).
(I need to find a way)
(أحتاج أن أجد طريقة)
(to take Xiaoxiao with me)
(لأخذ Xiaoxiao معي)
(to execute my plan.)
(لتنفيذ خطتي.)
(I don't want any unnecessary trouble.)
(لا أريد أي مشكلة لا داعي لها).
(Master.)
(يتقن.)
(I'll enter the Imperial Palace tomorrow.)
(سأدخل القصر الإمبراطوري غدًا.)
(Once I earn the Emperor's recognition,)
(بمجرد أن أحصل على تقدير الإمبراطور ،)
(the legacy of the Chen Theater Troupe)
(إرث فرقة مسرح تشين)
(will never be forgotten.)
(لن تنسى أبدا.)
Who's there?
من هناك؟
Youhai.
يوهاي.
Why are you here?
لماذا أنت هنا؟
Let's speak inside.
دعنا نتحدث في الداخل.
I found a lead on the fire.
لقد وجدت رصاصة على النار.
I plan
أنا أخطط
to finish my business in the Imperial Palace
لإنهاء عملي في القصر الإمبراطوري
before pursuing the lead.
قبل متابعة الصدارة.
If there's something more to the fire,
إذا كان هناك شيء آخر للنار ،
this return trip
رحلة العودة هذه
will be a dangerous one.
ستكون خطرة.
Perhaps
ربما
I can scout out everything first.
يمكنني استكشاف كل شيء أولاً.
You can stay in the Imperial Palace first.
يمكنك البقاء في القصر الإمبراطوري أولاً.
If I have something,
إذا كان لدي شيء ،
I'll notify you with a carrier pigeon.
سأخطرك مع الحمام الزاجل.
You can then come and join me.
يمكنك بعد ذلك المجيء والانضمام إلي.
No, Youhai.
لا ، يوهاي.
I'm not
أنالست
a coward.
جبان.
Master is like my father.
السيد مثل والدي.
You know what?
أتعلم؟
Once my performance is done,
بمجرد الانتهاء من أدائي ،
I'll come with you to investigate.
سآتي معك للتحقيق.
Okay.
تمام.
Go to bed earlier.
اذهب إلى الفراش مبكرًا.
♪The dusk outside the window is spreading♪
♪ الغسق خارج النافذة ينتشر
♪The lanterns light up with anticipation♪
الفوانيس تضيء بترقب
♪The sea of lights illuminates the entire theater♪
♪ بحر الأضواء ينير المسرح بأكمله
♪The galaxy sprawls across the sky♪
المجرة تمتد عبر السماء ♪
♪The moon shows itself♪
القمر يظهر نفسه ♪
♪Gazing at the myriad lives♪
التحديق في حياة لا تعد ولا تحصى ♪
♪The bell chimes and the lady dances♪
يدق الجرس والسيدة ترقص
♪Her movements are mysterious and graceful♪
حركاتها غامضة ورشيقة ♪
♪A woman can solicit cheers and applause too♪
♪ يمكن للمرأة أن تلتمس الهتافات والتصفيق أيضًا ♪
♪Chatters fill the well-lit hall♪
♪ الدردشة تملأ القاعة المضاءة جيدًا
♪Holding a red candle by the stage♪
♪ عقد شمعة حمراء على خشبة المسرح ♪
♪Witnessing the blooming and wilting, oh, the freedom♪
مشاهدة التفتح والذبول يا الحرية
♪The theater welcomes you♪
المسرح يرحب بك ♪